(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-12T10:34:39.669751",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
バンダイ・バンダイスピリッツより EXPO会場でも展示中の商品をご紹介！
Introducing products from Bandai and Bandai Spirits currently on display at the EXPO venue!
各種ECサイトで予約受付中！
Now accepting pre-orders on various e-commerce sites!
ウエハースや一番くじなど、たくさんの商品が発売いたします！
A wide variety of products, such as wafers and Ichiban Kuji, will be released!
ホロライブ ルームキー風アクリルチャーム
Hololive Room Key Acrylic Charms
#hololive IFシリーズより、「ロボ子さん」がRelax timeで登場予定！
From the #hololive IF series, Roboco-san is scheduled to appear in Relax time!
一番くじ ホロライブ アートアクリルコレクション
Ichiban Kuji Hololive Art Acrylic Collection
バンダイ／バンダイスピリッツブースでは会場限定グッズも無料配布中！
Free distribution of venue-limited goods at the Bandai / Bandai Spirits booths!
プレバンではすぐに使えるクーポンももらえるチャンス！
A chance to get coupons you can use right away on Premium Bandai!
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Weiß Schwarz!
楽しむ準備はいい？
Are you ready to have fun?
ヴァイスシュヴァルツの舞台でも青春しよう！
Let's have youth on the Weiß Schwarz stage too!
プレミアムブースター ホロライブプロダクション Summer Collection 3月22日(金)発売！
Premium Booster Hololive Production Summer Collection releases Friday, March 22!
ブシロード！
Bushiroad!
ホロスターズがヴァイスシュヴァルツブラウに登場！
HOLOSTARS appears in Weiß Schwarz Blau!
ようこそ、カードゲームの舞台へ！
Welcome to the card game stage!
ヴァイスシュヴァルツブラウ スタートデッキ＆ブースターパック ホロスターズ 好評発売中！
Weiß Schwarz Blau Start Deck & Booster Pack HOLOSTARS now on sale!
ブシロード！
Bushiroad!
hololive SUPER EXPO 2024開催を記念して、ホロライブメンバーのねんどろいどが新衣装になって再登場！
To commemorate hololive SUPER EXPO 2024, Hololive member Nendoroids return in new outfits!
新しいねんどろいどをお楽しみに！
Look forward to the new Nendoroids!
フリューから「ホロライブ」プライズが全国アミューズメント施設に
Hololive prizes from FuRyu are coming to amusement facilities nationwide
2024年7月以降に続々登場！
releasing one after another from July 2024 onward!
今後国内のホロライブメンバー全員展開予定！
Scheduled to roll out for all domestic Hololive members in the future!
最新情報はキャラ広場 ホロライブで検索！
Search "Chara Hiroba Hololive" for the latest info!
フリュー！
FuRyu!
あの涙が 今の僕らを繋いで
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に 君のカケラがいるから
Because a piece of you is in this heart,
一人じゃないから
Because we're not alone.
いつか描いた文字の中 目を閉じた先に色づく景色が揺れた
Within the words we drew someday, the scenery beyond closed eyes swayed.
少し戸惑う風の中（響く）
Amidst the slightly bewildered wind (echoing),
重なる花びら 私たちの声
Overlapping petals, our voices.
一瞬（一瞬） 一瞬（一瞬） 捕らえるみたいに
Like catching every single moment...
もっと（もっと）
If we could step forward
もっと踏み出せたら (we are one)
even more (we are one).
あの涙が 今の僕らを繋いで（繋いで）
Those tears connect us right now (connect us),
この心に 君のカケラがいるから
Because a piece of you is in this heart,
強くなくてもいい（なくてもいい）
It's okay not to be strong (it's okay),
今の光を
Gathering this light
僕と（君と） 集め（すべて） 空に放つ
with you and me (everything) and releasing it to the sky.
この奇跡を僕らで そっと輝かせるから（その手で）
Because we will softly make this miracle shine (with those hands).
力が湧くから
Strength wells up from within.
新たな種を握りしめ
Clenching a new seed in hand,
遠い未来へと 強く 願い 込め 撒い た
I scattered it toward the distant future with strong wishes.
希望 の 風 を 吹か せ て は （ 泳ぐ ）
Letting the wind of hope blow (swimming through it).
理想 の 花びら 祈る 明日 の 空
Petals of ideals, praying for tomorrow's sky.
何 百 （ 何 百 ） 億 も （ 億 も ）
Hundreds (hundreds), billions (billions) of
光る 星 みたい に
shining stars,
ずっと （ ずっと ）
forever (forever),
ずっと 終わら ない から
forever it will never end.
この笑顔が過去を強く抱きしめて（抱きしめて）
This smile strongly embraces the past (embraces it).
今未来にこの手伸ばしてゆくから
As I reach out my hand to the future now.
時 に 転ん で も （ それで いい ）
Even if we stumble sometimes (that's fine),
空 を 見上げ よう
let's look up at the sky.
笑い （ 泣い た ） 日々 を （ すべて ）
All the days we laughed (and cried),
刻ん で ゆく
carving them into time.
次の夢を掴み取るって約束するから
Promising to grasp our next dream,
（この手で）踏み出そう ここから
(with these hands) let's take a step forward from here.
(we are with you) (we are with you)
同じ未来を見ていたい
I want to see the same future.
あの夢手にしたい (we are with you , capture the moment)
I want to make that dream mine (we are with you, capture the moment).
触れ た 奇跡 の 中 で
Within the miracle we touched,
その先まで続く空にまぎれたら
if we blend into the sky extending beyond.
君 の 場所 と 今 を 繋ぎ たく て
Wanting to connect your place and the present.
あの涙が今の僕らを繋いで（繋いで）
Those tears connect us right now (connect us),
この心に君のカケラがいるから
Because a piece of you is in this heart,
強くなくてもいい（なくてもいい）
It's okay not to be strong (it's okay),
今の光を
Gathering this light
僕と（君と）集め（すべて）空に放つ
with you and me (everything) and releasing it to the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから
Because we will softly make this miracle shine.
（この手で）咲かせよう ここから（一緒に）
Let's make flowers bloom from here (together).
一人じゃないから (we are one)
Because we're not alone (we are one).
あの涙が 今の僕らを繋いで
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に 君のカケラがいるから
Because a piece of you is in this heart,
一人じゃないから
Because we're not alone.
いつか描いた文字の中 目目を閉じた先に色づく景色が揺れた
Within the words we drew someday, the scenery beyond closed eyes swayed.
少し戸惑う風の中（響く）
Amidst the slightly bewildered wind (echoing),
重なる花びら 私たちの声
Overlapping petals, our voices.
一瞬（一瞬） 一瞬（一瞬） 捕らえるみたいに
Like catching every single moment...
もっと（もっと）もっと踏み出せたら (we are one)
If we could step forward even more (we are one).
あの涙が 今の僕らを繋いで（繋いで）
Those tears connect us right now (connect us),
この心に 君のカケラがいるから
Because a piece of you is in this heart,
強くなくてもいい（なくてもいい）
It's okay not to be strong (it's okay),
今の光を
Gathering this light
僕と（君と） 集め（すべて） 空に放つ
with you and me (everything) and releasing it to the sky.
この奇跡を僕らで そっと輝かせるから（その手で）
Because we will softly make this miracle shine (with those hands).
力が湧くから
Strength wells up from within.
新たな種を握りしめ
Clenching a new seed in hand,
遠い未来へと 強く 願い 込め 撒い た
I scattered it toward the distant future with strong wishes.
希望 の 風 を 吹か せ て は （ 泳ぐ ）
Letting the wind of hope blow (swimming through it).
理想 の 花びら 祈る 明日 の 空
Petals of ideals, praying for tomorrow's sky.
何 百 （ 何 百 ） 億 も （ 億 も ）
Hundreds (hundreds), billions (billions) of
光る 星 みたい に
shining stars,
ずっと （ ずっと ）
forever (forever),
ずっと 終わら ない から
forever it will never end.
この笑顔が過去を強く抱きしめて（抱きしめて）
This smile strongly embraces the past (embraces it).
今未来にこの手伸ばしてゆくから
As I reach out my hand to the future now.
時 に 転ん で も （ それで いい ）
Even if we stumble sometimes (that's fine),
空 を 見上げ よう
let's look up at the sky.
笑い （ 泣い た ） 日々 を （ すべて ）
All the days we laughed (and cried),
刻ん で ゆく
carving them into time.
次の夢を掴み取るって約束するから
Promising to grasp our next dream,
（この手で）踏み出そう ここから
(with these hands) let's take a step forward from here.
あの涙が今の僕らを繋いで
Those tears connect us now,
この心に君の欠片がいるから
because pieces of you live in this heart.
一人じゃないから
We are not alone.
いつか描いた文字の中 目を閉じた先に
In words once drawn, beyond closed eyes,
色づく景色が揺れた
the coloring scenery swayed.
少し戸惑う風の中 重なる花びら 私たちの声
In a slightly hesitant breeze, our voices overlap like falling petals.
一瞬一瞬捕らえるみたいに もっともっともっと踏み出せたら
Catching every single instant, step forward even more!
あの涙が今の僕らを繋いで
Those tears connect us now,
この心に君の欠片がいるから
because pieces of you live in this heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を僕と君と集め全て空に放つ
It's okay not to be strong. Let's gather the light of now with you and release it to the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせることができるから
We will gently make this miracle shine with these hands.
力が湧くから
Strength wells up from within.
新たな種を握りしめ 遠い未来へと強く願い込め撒いた
Clutching a new seed, we scattered it with a strong wish for a distant future.
希望の風を吹かせては 理想の花びら祈る明日の空
Blowing the winds of hope, the ideal flowers pray for tomorrow's sky.
何百億も光る星みたいに
Like hundreds of millions of shining stars,
ずーっとずーっとずーっと終わらないから
it will never, ever, ever end.
この笑顔が過去を強く抱きしめて
This smile strongly embraces the past,
今未来にこの手伸ばしてゆくから
so we will reach out our hands to the future now.
時に転んでも 空を見上げよう
Even if we stumble sometimes, let's look up at the sky.
笑い泣いた日々を全て刻んでゆく
Carving out every smiling and weeping day,
次の夢を掴み取るって約束するから
we promise to seize the next dream with these hands.
踏み出そうここから
Let's step out from here!
同じ未来を見ていたい
We want to see the same future.
あの夢手にしたい
We want that dream in our hands.
触れた奇跡の中で その先まで続く空にまぎれたら
Caught in the touch of a miracle, if we get swept into the sky that continues beyond,
君の場所と今を繋ぎたくて
we want to connect your place and the present.
あの涙が今の僕らを繋いで
Those tears connect us now,
この心に君の欠片がいるから
because pieces of you live in this heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を集め空に放つ
It's okay not to be strong. Let's gather the light of now and release it to the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせることができるから
We will gently make this miracle shine with these hands.
咲かせようここから一緒に
Let's make them bloom from here together,
一人じゃないから
because we are not alone.
あの涙が今の僕らをつないで
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に君のカケラがいるから 一人じゃないから
because your fragments are in my heart, and I'm not alone.
いつか描いた文字の中
Within the words we drew someday,
目を閉じた先に色づく景色が揺れた
the colorful scenery beyond closed eyes swayed.
少し戸惑う風の中
In the slightly bewildered wind
重なる花びら 私たちの声
overlapping petals, our voices
一瞬 一瞬 一瞬 捕まえるみたいに
as if catching every single moment
もっと もっと もっと踏み出せたら 【we are one】
if we could step forward more and more... we are one.
あの涙が今の僕らをつないで
Those tears connect us right now
この心に君のカケラがいるから
because your fragments are in my heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong; this present light
僕と 集め 空に放つ
I will gather with you and release into the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから 力が湧くから
We'll make this miracle gently shine together, giving us strength.
新しい種を握りしめ
Grasping new seeds tightly,
遠い未来へと強く願い込め蒔いた
we sowed them with strong wishes toward the distant future.
希望の風を吹かせては
Letting the wind of hope blow,
理想の花びら祈る明日の空
ideal petals pray for tomorrow's sky.
何百 億も 光る星みたいに
Like hundreds of millions of shining stars,
ずっと ずっと ずっと終わらないから
it will never, ever end.
この笑顔が過去を強く抱きしめて
This smile tightly embraces the past,
今未来にこの手伸ばしていくから
as I reach out my hands to the future now.
時に転んでも 空を見上げよう
Even if we stumble sometimes, let's look up at the sky.
笑い 日々を 刻んでゆく
Carving out days of laughter and tears,
次の夢を手に入れるって約束するから 踏み出そうここから
I promise to seize the next dream, so let's step forward from here.
(we are with you we are with you)
同じ未来を見ていたい あの夢手にしたい
wanting to see the same future, wanting that dream in hand.
(we are with you capture the moment)
その先 まで 続く空にまぎれ たら
mingling into the endless sky beyond.
君の場所と今をつなぎたくて
Wanting to connect your place with the present,
あの涙が今の僕らをつないで
those tears connect us right now
この心に君のカケラがいるから
because your fragments are in my heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong; this present light
僕と 集め 空に放つ
I will gather with you and release into the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから
We'll make this miracle gently shine together,
咲かせようここから 一緒に
let's make it bloom from here, together.
一人じゃないから 【we are one】
Because we're not alone, we are one.
あの涙が今の僕らをつないで
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に君のカケラがいるから 一人じゃないから
because your fragments are in my heart, and I'm not alone.
いつか描いた文字の中
Within the words we drew someday,
目を閉じた先に色づく景色が揺れた
the colorful scenery beyond closed eyes swayed.
少し戸惑う風の中
In the slightly bewildered wind
重なる花びら 私たちの声
overlapping petals, our voices
一瞬 一瞬 一瞬 捕まえるみたいに
as if catching every single moment
もっと もっと もっと踏み出せたら 【we are one】
if we could step forward more and more... we are one.
あの涙が今の僕らをつないで
Those tears connect us right now
この心に君のカケラがいるから
because your fragments are in my heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong; this present light
僕と 集め 空に放つ
I will gather with you and release into the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから 力が湧くから
We'll make this miracle gently shine together, giving us strength.
新しい種を握りしめ
Grasping new seeds tightly,
遠い未来へと強く願い込め蒔いた
we sowed them with strong wishes toward the distant future.
希望の風を吹かせては
Letting the wind of hope blow,
理想の花びら祈る明日の空
ideal petals pray for tomorrow's sky.
何百 億も 光る星みたいに
Like hundreds of millions of shining stars,
ずっと ずっと ずっと終わらないから
it will never, ever end.
この笑顔が過去を強く抱きしめて
This smile tightly embraces the past,
今未来にこの手伸ばしていくから
as I reach out my hands to the future now.
時に転んでも 空を見上げよう
Even if we stumble sometimes, let's look up at the sky.
笑い 日々を 刻んでゆく
Carving out days of laughter and tears,
次の夢を手に入れるって約束するから 踏み出そうここから
I promise to seize the next dream, so let's step forward from here.
(we are with you we are with you)
同じ未来を見ていたい あの夢手にしたい
wanting to see the same future, wanting that dream in hand.
(we are with you capture the moment)
その先 まで 続く空にまぎれ たら
mingling into the endless sky beyond.
君の場所と今をつなぎたくて
Wanting to connect your place with the present,
あの涙が今の僕らをつないで
those tears connect us right now
この心に君のカケラがいるから
because your fragments are in my heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong; this present light
僕と 集め 空に放つ
I will gather with you and release into the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから
We'll make this miracle gently shine together,
咲かせようここから 一緒に
let's make it bloom from here, together.
一人じゃないから 【we are one】
Because we're not alone, we are one.
(we are with you we are with you)
同じ未来を見ていたい あの夢手にしたい
wanting to see the same future, wanting that dream in hand.
(we are with you capture the moment)
その先 まで 続く空にまぎれ たら
mingling into the endless sky beyond.
君の場所と今をつなぎたくて
Wanting to connect your place with the present,
あの涙が今の僕らをつないで
those tears connect us right now
この心に君のカケラがいるから
because your fragments are in my heart.
あの涙が 今の僕らを つないで
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に君のカケラがあるから
Because fragments of you are in this heart,
一人じゃないから
Because we are not alone.
いつか描いた文字の中
Within the letters we drew one day,
目を閉じた先に色づく景色が揺れた
The colors swayed beyond closed eyes.
少し戸惑う風の中 (響く)
In the slightly hesitant wind (echoing),
重なる花びら 私たちの声
Overlapping petals, our voices.
一瞬 (一瞬) 一瞬 (一瞬) 捕らえるみたいに
Like capturing every single moment,
もっと (もっと) もっと踏み出せばほら
Stepping out even further, look...
あの涙が 今の僕らを つないで
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に 君のカケラがあるから
Because fragments of you are in this heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
Even if we aren't strong, this light now,
僕と 集め 空に放つ
Gathered with you, released into the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから
We'll make this miracle softly shine from here.
新たな種を握りしめ
Clutching new seeds in our hands,
遠い未来へと強く願い込め撒いた
We scattered them with strong prayers for the distant future.
希望の風を吹かせては
Letting the winds of hope blow,
理想の花びら 祈る明日の空
Ideal petals praying for tomorrow's sky.
何百億も光る星みたいに
Like hundreds of millions of shining stars,
ずっと終わらないから
It will never end.
この笑顔が過去を強く抱きしめて
This smile firmly embraces the past,
今未来にこの手伸ばしてゆくから
As we reach out our hands to the future now.
時に転んでも 空を見上げよう
Even if we stumble sometimes, let's look up at the sky.
笑い 日々を 刻んでゆく
Engraving every smiling day.
次の夢を掴み取るって約束するから
Promising to seize our next dream from here.
同じ未来を見 ていたい
Wanting to see the same future together,
あの夢手にしたい
Wanting that dream in our hands.
触れた奇跡の中で
Within the miracle we touched,
その先まで続く空にまぎれたら
If we blend into the sky extending beyond,
君の場所と今をつなぎたくて
We want to connect your place with right now.
あの涙が 今の僕らを つないで
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に 君のカケラがあるから
Because fragments of you are in this heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
Even if we aren't strong, this light now,
僕と 集め 空に放つ
Gathered with you, released into the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから
We'll make this miracle softly shine from here.
咲かせよう ここから
Let's make it bloom from here.
一人じゃないから
Because we are not alone.
あの涙が 今の僕らを つないで
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に君のカケラがあるから
Because fragments of you are in this heart,
一人じゃないから
Because we are not alone.
いつか描いた文字の中
Within the letters we drew one day,
目を閉じた先に色づく景色が揺れた
The colors swayed beyond closed eyes.
少し戸惑う風の中
In the slightly hesitant wind,
重なる花びら 私たちの声
Overlapping petals, our voices.
一瞬 捕らえるみたいに
Like capturing every single moment,
もっと もっと踏み出せばほら
Stepping out even further, look...
あの涙が 今の僕らを つないで
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に 君のカケラがあるから
Because fragments of you are in this heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
Even if we aren't strong, this light now,
僕と 集め 空に放つ
Gathered with you, released into the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから
We'll make this miracle softly shine from here.
新たな種を握りしめ
Clutching new seeds in our hands,
遠い未来へと強く願い込め撒いた
We scattered them with strong prayers for the distant future.
希望の風を吹かせては
Letting the winds of hope blow,
理想の花びら 祈る明日の空
Ideal petals praying for tomorrow's sky.
何百億も光る星みたいに
Like hundreds of millions of shining stars,
ずっと終わらないから
It will never end.
この笑顔が過去を強く抱きしめて
This smile firmly embraces the past,
今未来にこの手伸ばしてゆくから
As we reach out our hands to the future now.
時に転んでも 空を見上げよう
Even if we stumble sometimes, let's look up at the sky.
笑い 日々を 刻んでゆく
Engraving every smiling day.
次の夢を掴み取るって約束するから
Promising to seize our next dream from here.
同じ未来を見 ていたい
Wanting to see the same future together,
あの夢手にしたい
Wanting that dream in our hands.
触れた奇跡の中で
Within the miracle we touched,
その先まで続く空にまぎれたら
If we blend into the sky extending beyond,
君の場所と今をつなぎたくて
We want to connect your place with right now.
あの涙が 今の僕らを つないで
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に 君のカケラがあるから
Because fragments of you are in this heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
Even if we aren't strong, this light now,
僕と 集め 空に放つ
Gathered with you, released into the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから
We'll make this miracle softly shine from here.
咲かせよう ここから
Let's make it bloom from here.
一人じゃないから
Because we are not alone.
あの涙が 今の僕らを つないで
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に 君のカケラがあるから
Because fragments of you are in this heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
Even if we aren't strong, this light now,
僕と 集め 空に放つ
Gathered with you, released into the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから
We'll make this miracle softly shine from here.
同じ未来を見 ていたい
Wanting to see the same future together,
あの夢手にしたい
Wanting that dream in our hands.
触れた奇跡の中で
Within the miracle we touched,
その先まで続く空にまぎれたら
If we blend into the sky extending beyond,
君の場所と今をつなぎたくて
We want to connect your place with right now.
あの涙が 今の僕らを つないで
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に 君のカケラがあるから
Because fragments of you are in this heart.
一人じゃないから
Because we are not alone.
hololive 5th fes. #hololivesfes EXPO24_DAY1
hololive 5th fes. EXPO 2024 - DAY 1
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention to Visitors
hololive SUPER EXPO 2024 & hololive 5th fes. オフィシャルグッズ販売期間
hololive SUPER EXPO 2024 & hololive 5th fes. Official Goods Sales Period
Parade, Parade, Parade 輝きを組んだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade, weaved with brilliance
呼び合う声を合図に
With our calling voices as a signal
Parade, Parade, Parade 探しに行こう
Parade, Parade, Parade, let's go search
言葉は無くたって
Even without words
ひとりごとつぶった
Murmured to myself alone
ただ始まりたくて走った
I just ran, wanting it to begin
遠く暗がりに止まった
Stopping in the distant darkness
それは眩しすぎた名前
That was a name far too dazzling
それは切なすぎる想いで
That was with feelings far too painful
もっと近づけと手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand to get closer
想いだけぶつかりあった
Only our feelings collided
ほら今迷子は本来の旅だ
Look, now the stray is on its true journey
Parade, Parade, Parade 輝きを組んだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade, weaved with brilliance
増やした想い一つずつ
Each and every increased memory
風穴抜け出せるさ
We can break through the wind hole
輝かない祈りばっかり
Only prayers that don't shine
終わりなき傷跡
Endless scars
君を見つけたこと
Finding you
夢を始めるよ
Starting our dream
ここからこれから甘くない Parade, Parade
From here, from now, not a sweet Parade
parade, parade, parade!
光るんだよ 呼び合う声を合図に
Shining bright, taking cues from our calling voices!
parade, parade, parade! 探しにゆく
Parade, parade, parade! We'll go search for it,
スタートは何回だって
no matter how many times we start over!
ただ独り言を紡いだ
I wove together my lonely murmurs,
ただ始まりたくて走った
and ran just because I wanted to begin.
遠く暗がりに行灯した
Lighting a lantern in the distant gloom—
それは眩し過ぎた名前
that name was far too blinding.
それは優し過ぎる思い出もずっと
And those memories were far too kind,
近づけと手を伸ばした
so I reached out my hand to draw close.
思いがけず結び合った
Unexpectedly, our paths intertwined,
ほら今迷子は「僕等」になった
and look, the lost ones became "us."
parade, parade, parade!
光るんだよ
Shining bright,
悔しさも愛しさも連れておいでで
bringing along both our regrets and our love!
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings—you can take flight!
ささやかな祈りは光 終わりなき兆し
A modest prayer becomes light, an endless omen.
君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
Finding you is something I can be proud of!
ここから ここから
From here, from now on,
our bright parade, parade!
まだ頼りない予感を抑え切れない
I can't suppress this unreliable premonition.
歌おう恥ずかしかなんてないよ
Let's sing! There's nothing to be shy about.
誰も解けないイマジナリー
An imaginary world no one can decode,
いつかまた逢えるおまじない
a spell to meet again someday.
あの日子どもに始まったストーリー
A story that began as children back then,
数え切れない言の葉
with countless words and leaves...
数えような想いじゃないさ
not feelings that can be easily counted.
ほら今「僕等」を一つと呼ぼう
Look, let's call "us" as one right now!
parade, parade, parade! 美しいんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's so beautiful.
許し合える刹那 夜はきらめく
A fleeting moment of mutual forgiveness as the night sparkles.
雨 晴れ カレイド またとない空
Rain, shine, kaleidoscope—a one-of-a-kind sky.
相応しい旅路とは 君と在ることさ
A fitting journey means being right by your side!
「ただいま」を聞けば「おかえり」って叫ぶよ
Hearing "I'm home," I shout back "Welcome home!"
当たり前じゃないか 君と取り戻してゆく素敵な続き
Isn't that only natural as we reclaim this wonderful continuation?
ここから それから Our Bright Parade, Parade!
From here, from then on, Our Bright Parade, Parade!
parade, parade, parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! Shining bright,
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ！
filling the darkness are you and I!
ド・キ・ド・キ・して rouge ？
Making your heart race with rouge?
【いっけましょ～！】
[Let's go!]
（無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！）
[Innocent! Innocent! Pretty girl innocent!]
（マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！）
[Marine! Marine! Marine is innocent!]
（やっぱりキラキラ もっとクラクラ）
[Always sparkling, spinning even more!]
ねえ、言ったよね？
Hey, you told me so, right?
年齢なんて関係ないってさ
That age doesn't matter at all,
そういうめんどくさいのも含めて愛してくれるって
and that you'd love me with all my troublesome traits!
ねえ、言ったよね？
Hey, you said that, didn't you?
言ってない？
Or did you not?
ふーん、そういうこというんだ
Hmm, is that what you say?
ちなみにこの船では美少女無罪が適用されますけど？
By the way, the "Pretty Girl Innocence" law applies on this ship!
まかせて！魔法で若返り ミキツの素顔はキミにだけ【トクベツですよ～！】
Leave it to me! Rejuvenated by magic, my true face is just for you—[It's a special treat!]
あぁ…アタシ厄介よ あぁ…港なんかじゃしゃあないわ近頃ね
Ah... I'm a handful. Ah... staying in port isn't easy lately either,
宝の島にしてほしい気分【出航ーー！】
feeling like I want to make it an island of treasure—[Set sail!]
キュートは正義 美少女無罪
Cute is justice, pretty girl innocence!
キミの一番目指して ヨーソロー！
Aiming to be your number one, yosoro!
本当は自信ないけど 頑張っちゃう
I'm not really confident, but I'll do my best!
【ahoy！！】きゅっきゅっきゅるん きゅっきゅっきゅるんるん
[Ahoy!!] Kyu-kyu-kyurun, kyu-kyu-kyurun-run!
恋する気持ち17歳 0時（てっぺん）になっちゃうわ オトナの時間
Feeling in love at 17, turning midnight—adult time!
（やっぱりキラキラ もっとクラクラ）
[Always sparkling, spinning even more!]
ド・キ・ド・キ・して rouge ？ まだ早い♡
Making your heart race with rouge? Still too early♡
だっだ、ダメですか？ フリルの お召し換え？
Is, is, is that no good? Changing into frills?
だっだだだって 魔法少女になってみたい
B-B-Because I want to try becoming a magical girl!
【ぎりぎり有罪！？】
[Barely guilty!?]
進路はなんほんせい とちょっぴり足んない積極性？
Our course has no real direction, and our initiative is a bit lacking?
（結局キミももっと若い子？なんかっつーから見捨てないで、キミたち！）
[In the end, you prefer younger girls? Don't abandon us after saying that, you guys!]
（ちょっとイイニコ 見てみたい～！）
[I want to see a little friendly smile~!]
あぁ…たまにいじけちゃう あぁ…それでもいいのかい？
Ah... sometimes I get sullen. Ah... is even that okay with you?
年頃なもんで 本気になっちゃう嵐の中も【一緒に行こう！】
Being my age, I get serious even in the middle of a storm—[Let's go together!]
【出航ーー！】ハートにチャーム 美少女無罪
[Set sail!] Charm on my heart, pretty girl innocence!
あれあれどうしたの？ めんどくさいって言いかっちゃって
What's wrong? Saying things are too troublesome,
かまってくれるキミが好き【ahoy！！】
but I love when you pay attention to me [Ahoy!!]
きゅっきゅっきゅるん きゅっきゅっきゅるんるん 優しくしてね17歳
Kyu-kyu-kyurun, kyu-kyu-kyurun-run, be gentle with me at 17!
突っ込んで経験値 お楽しみchu♡（やっぱりキラキラ もっとクラクラ）
Plunging in for experience points, enjoying the chu♡ (Always sparkling, spinning even more!)
ド・キ・ド・キ・して rouge ？ あぁ、お許しくだた～い！
Making your heart race with rouge? Ah, please forgive me~!
このマリンの…【魅力！魔力！不抗力！！】──“罪な女”ね？
This Marine's... [Charm! Magic! Irresistible force!!] -- You're a "sinful woman," huh?
離さないでつかまっていて 世界の広さ見せてあげるから！【出航ーー！】
Hold on tight and don't let go, I'll show you how big the world is! [Set sail!]
キュートは正義 美少女無罪 キミの一番目指して ヨーソロー！
Cute is justice, pretty girl innocence! Aiming to be your number one, yosoro!
冗談も大好きだけど 真剣よ【ahoy！！】
I love jokes too, but I'm dead serious [Ahoy!!]
きゅっきゅっきゅるん きゅっきゅっきゅるんるん 恋する気持ち17歳
Kyu-kyu-kyurun, kyu-kyu-kyurun-run, feeling in love at 17,
0時になっちゃうわ オトナの時間（やっぱりキラキラ もっとクラクラ）
turning midnight—adult time! (Always sparkling, spinning even more!)
ド・キ・ド・キ・して rouge ？ まだ早い♡
Making your heart race with rouge? Still too early♡
（無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！） （マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！）
(Innocent! Innocent! Pretty girl innocent!) (Marine! Marine! Marine is innocent!)
（やっぱりキラキラ もっとクラクラ）
(Always sparkling, spinning even more!)
【“マリン”ではなくて“マリン船長”だろうん！？】
[It's not just "Marine," it's "Captain Marine"!]
ドキドキして ヌー
With my heart racing, nuu!
お許しくだされ
Please forgive me!
この御御足の
These legs of mine,
魅力
charm,
火力
firepower,
暴力
violence,
美麗な女で
I'm a gorgeous woman!
手玉に取っていて
Playing you in the palm of my hand,
絶対の自由を貯め込んであげるから
I'll save up absolute freedom for you!
魅惑の世界で
In this alluring world,
あなたを奪いたい 君の一番
I want to steal you, your number one!
きゅんきゅるんきゅん きゅんきゅるるん
Kyun kyurun kyun, kyun kyururun
すれっすれのキスマーク無駄にするな
Don't waste that close-call kiss mark!
てっぺん見なしちゃうぞ 大人の時間
I'll make you look at the top, adult time!
ドキドキして ヌー
With my heart racing, nuu,
まだ早い
it's still too early!
マリンじゃなくて
Not Marine,
マリン船長だろ！
Captain Marine!
美少女無罪♡パイレーツ
Bishoujou Muzai Pirates!
真夜中に トケタ感情は爪立てて 檻から
In the dead of night, melted emotions bare claws from the cage,
見慣れた世界は牙向いて 優しさ伝えたんだ
the familiar world bares fangs, wanting to convey kindness.
ニャンニャカナ リンリン リン おねだり
Nyan-nyakana, ring-ring-ring, begging,
さあ手懐けてよ もっとめいっぱい！
come on, tame me to the fullest!
ニャンニャカナ リンリン リン おでかけ？
Nyan-nyakana, ring-ring-ring, going out?
しがみついて何処も行かせない！
Clinging on, I won't let you go anywhere!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャニュ ウー
Uunyaka, nyan-nya-nyu, uo,
甘いキャンディ頂戴な
give me sweet candy!
本当の「好き」頂戴な
Give me your true 'I love you'!
縄張り土足で感情目眩しして
Stomping into my territory and dazzling my emotions,
幸せになれた未来が牙向いて
the future where I found happiness bares its fangs,
突き放さないでいて 愛の群れに飲み込まれてく
don't push me away, swallowed by the flock of love.
コンコンとこんがらがっていく感情
Feelings getting tangled up more and more,
金曜日足踏みし 褒めを広がれ序章で
stepping on my feet on Friday, expanding praise in the intro.
貰ってばかりじゃ 嫌！ 泣いちゃうから
Just receiving things is no good! I'll cry!
手手繋いで いつでも手首
Holding hands, always wrists,
追いついて交点
catching up at the intersection.
聞き届けておねだり 恥ずかしがらないで
Grant my plea and beg, don't be shy!
誕生日も記念日も 一緒に彩ろう
Birthdays and anniversaries too, let's color them together!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャニュ ウー
Uunyaka, nyan-nya-nyu, uo,
甘いキャンディ頂戴な
give me sweet candy,
あーラブ・ル・ル
ah, love ru ru!
散らかったあとの祭りに取り合えず全部突っ込み
Stuffing everything into the post-mess festival for now
不協和音不気味お洒落したがりに浸ってるって感じ
Feeling like I'm soaking in a spooky desire to dress up
高精度おはよう高速
High-precision morning high speed,
留まって詰めて 連生でいいんですか
stopping and packing, is winning streak okay?
優勝しちゃったわ 同情できない 先輩後輩
I ended up winning, can't sympathize, seniors and juniors
みんなで作って 温かかった好きが
The warmth created by everyone of liking
好きがずっと続いてく 見守るんだ
The feeling of love continues forever, watching over us
お騒がせの今
Right now causing a commotion
のりのり すきすき のりすき
Nori-nori, suki-suki, nori-suki,
nori-nori, suki-suki, nori-suki,
のりのり すきすき のりすき
お互い大好きを愛してよ 一緒にしようよ
Love each other's great love, let's do it together!
思いっきり想い愛を 覆い隠して
Covering up heavy love with all my might,
少し反省改めて今日も大好き
reflecting a little and renewing my love today too
手手繋いで いつでも手首
Holding hands, always wrists,
追いついて交点
catching up at the intersection,
聞き届けておねだり 恥ずかしがらないで
grant my plea and beg, don't be shy!
誕生日も記念日も 一緒に彩ろう
birthdays and anniversaries too, let's color them together!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャニュ ウー
Uunyaka, nyan-nya-nyu, uo,
甘いキャンディ頂戴な
give me sweet candy,
あーラブ・ル・ル 白かしたあとの祭り
ah, love ru ru, at the post-mess festival
愛！愛！愛！愛！
Love! Love! Love! Love!
お祭りわっしょい！
Festival wasshoi!
お・た・か・く・さ・い・こう！
Highest of highs!
ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どんどン
Gyu, don, gyu, don, gyu, don, don
ギュッとしてドーン！
Let's do it like this!
ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どんどン
Gyu, don, gyu, don, gyu, don, don
ギュッとしてドーン！
Let's do it like this!
ポロポロかあててサッパリとハッピーハッピーハッピー！
Drop on by, step right in, happy happy, happy!
ほかに温もりは、いーいー？
With others, it's nice and cozy, but...
ぎゅの、の、中は、り、り、り、り、リトル？
In the depths of my heart, I wonder...
スープやオムライス、トッピングはお好み？おいし〜！
Soup or rice, or maybe a bento - everything is delicious!
どれも最高！笑顔で決めちゃいなよ！
Let's make this our final smile!
はーい？ほらてこのバブちゃんたち、こぢんまりでしよ？
Hey, why don't we get all lovey-dovey and cozy together?
食べる前にお姉さんと運動、きんもちおね！
Before that, let's exercise with big sis!
えーびフライ、たーな、ふー、あゆ、はんぐりー？
Fried shrimp, fried oysters, are you hungry?
ぎゅ、ぎゅ、ぎゅ、ぎゅ！
Gyu, gyu, gyu, gyu!
からのおいしくいただきます！
I'd love to have some, please!
ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どんどン
Gyu, don, gyu, don, gyu, don, don
一緒に食べよう！めーいっぱいよーくかんばる！とろとろちゅわわ！
Let's eat it together! With all our might, let's survive!
ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どんどン
Gyu, don, gyu, don, gyu, don, don
ごろりお肉、お肉、つーまみょのうえ！ぜんぶ食べちゃいなんだ！ほめちゃう！
Meat, meat, let's finish it all up!
なべなべよしよしちゅ、ちゅ、ちゅ！
Nabe, nabe, yoshi-yoshi, chu, chu, chu!
ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どんどン
Gyu, don, gyu, don, gyu, don, don
えっ？ぎゅどんが嫌い？
Huh? You don't like gyudon?
もう！なんでそんなこと言うの！そんな悪い子は...
Why would you say something like that? That's so mean!
食べちゃうぞ！
...eaten up!
ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どんどン
Gyu, don, gyu, don, gyu, don, don
よくできました！カフェにちゅう！
We did it! We stayed safe in our little café!
ところが全然とろけません！
Wait, the cheese isn't melting at all!
だくだく、つゆだく！
Daku daku, tsuyu daku...
それでも全然とろけません！
Even so, it's still not melting at all!
だくだく、にくたぬ！
Daku daku, niku daku...
まだまだ全然足りないの！
There's still nowhere near enough!
だくだく、どくどく！ときがむねむねとまらない！
Daku daku, doku doku! My heart just won't stop pounding!
ぎゅうどんを食べるときは、お口でふーふーしてって、て、
When eating gyudon, you scoop it up with your mouth...
あ、いきなりがついちゃって、かわいい！
Ah, you went and did it all of a sudden! How cute!
やさしく丁寧に、ね？
Let's do it gently and carefully, okay?
いいこいいこ、おなかいっぱいになっちゃったね、いっしょにねちゃう？おやすみなさい！
Good boy, good girl! Your tummy is totally full, isn't it? Should we sleep together? Good night!
もしも君がしゅんとしちゃっても...
What if you act all sulky and pouty?
ぎゅってぎゅってぎゅって、だきしめてあげる！
I'll hold you tight, squeeze you tight, and hug you so close!
みんなでうたおう！
Let's all sing together!
ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どんどン
Gyu, don, gyu, don, gyu, don, don
一緒に食べよう！
Let's eat it together!
せめと何回でもハニバる！とろとろちゅわわ！
No matter how many times, let's keep running and getting cozy, with everyone's love!
ごろりお肉、お肉、つーまみょのだめ！
Soup or meat, everything is just too good!
ぜーんぶ食べたんだ褒めちゃう！なでなでよしよしちゅ！
Let's finish it all and praise each other!
ちゅちゅ！
Chu, chu!
ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どん、ぎゅ、どんどン
Gyu, don, gyu, don, gyu, don, don
だいすき、ぎゅっとしてどーん、まだまだどーん！
Love it, love it! Do it like this and...
すろがねのえでのぎゅ、どん、どーん！ぎゅーい！
A gyudon drawn on the folding screen! Gyu!
ド・キ・ド・キ し て rouge ?
Does your pulse race through the rouge?
いきますよー！
Here we go!
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
Not guilty! Not guilty! Beautiful girl not guilty!
マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！
Marine! Marine! Marine is not guilty!
やっぱり キラキラ もっと クラクラ
Brilliant and sparkling, making me dizzy!
ねえ、言ったよね？
Hey, didn't you say it?
年齢なんて関係ないってさ
Age doesn't matter at all!
そうゆうめんどさいのも含めて愛してくれるって
You'll love me even with all my flaws.
ねえねえ、言ったよね？言ってない？
Hey hey, didn't you say it? Did you not?
ふーん、そういうこというんだ
Hmm, so that's how it is.
ちなみにこの船では
By the way, on this ship,
美少女無罪が適用されますけど？
\"Not guilty for beautiful girls\" applies!
まかせて！魔法で若返り
Leave it to me! Magic makes me young again.
ヒミツの素顔はキミにだけトクベツですー？
My secret true face is just for you!
Ah… アタシ厄介よ
Ah... I'm a handful.
Ah… 港なんかじゃしがないわ 近頃はね
Ah... I can't get excited at ports anymore.
宝島にしてほしい気分
I feel like turning it into a treasure island!
出航──！！
Set sail!
キュートは正義 美少女無罪
Cute is justice, beautiful girls are not guilty.
キミの一番目指して ヨーソロー！
Aimed to be your number one, steady as she goes!
本当は自信ないけど 頑張っちゃう
I'm actually not confident, but I'll do my best!
ahoy！！
Ahoy!
きゅっ きゅっ きゅるん きゅっ きゅっ きゅるん
Kyu kyu kyurun, kyu kyu kyurun.
恋する 気持ち 17才
A heart in love, sweet 17.
0時(テッペン)になっちゃうワ オトナの時間
It's midnight, adult time!
やっぱり キラキラ もっと クラクラ
Brilliant and sparkling, making me dizzy!
ド・キ・ド・キ し て rouge ?
Does your pulse race through the rouge?
まだ早い ♡
Not yet!
だっだっ ダメですか？
I-I-Is it no good?
フリルの召し物着たらば
If I wear frilly clothes...
（そんなこと、ないよ）
(No, that's not true!)
だっだっ だって 魔女っ子になってみたい
B-B-Because I want to try being a magical girl!
ギリギリ有罪！？
Barely guilty?!
進路はなんない星
Our course is to Whatever-Star.
ちょっぴり足んない積極性？
Lacking a bit of assertiveness?
結局キミももっと若い子？
In the end, do you prefer younger girls too?
なんにしたって見捨てないでキミたち！
No matter what, don't abandon us, you guys!
（ちょっとイイコト見せてみたーい！）
(Want to see something nice?!)
Ah… たまにいじけちゃう
Ah... Sometimes I sulk.
Ah… それでもいいの？
Ah... Is that okay?
年頃だもん 本気になっちゃう
I'm at that age, so I get serious.
嵐の中も
Even through stormy seas,
一緒に、行こう？
shall we go together?
出航──！！
Set sail!
ハートにチャーム 美少女無罪
Charm on your heart, beautiful girls are not guilty.
あれあれどうした？
Well, well, what's wrong?
めんどさいよなんて言っちゃってさ
You complain that it's troublesome, but still...
かまってくれるキミが好き
I love you for paying attention to me!
ahoy！！
Ahoy!
きゅっ きゅっ きゅるん きゅっ きゅっ きゅるんるん
Kyu kyu kyurun, kyu kyu kyururun.
優しくしてね 17才
Be gentle with me, sweet 17.
突っ込んで経験値 お楽しみchu ♡
Dive into experience, enjoy chu ♡
やっぱり キラキラ もっと クラクラ
Brilliant and sparkling, making me dizzy!
ド・キ・ド・キ し て rouge ?
Does your pulse race through the rouge?
あぁ、お許しくだーたい！
Ah, please forgive me!
このマリンの……
This Marine's...
魅力！魔力！抗不可力！
Charm! Magic! Irresistible force!
──“罪な女”ね？
You're a \"sinful woman\", huh?
離さないで つかまっていて
Don't let go, hold on tight!
世界の広さ 見せたげるから！
I'll show you how big the world is!
出航──！！
Set sail!
キュートは正義 美少女無罪
Cute is justice, beautiful girls are not guilty.
キミの一番目指して ヨーソロー！
Aimed to be your number one, steady as she goes!
冗談も大好きだけど 真剣よ
I love jokes too, but I'm serious!
ahoy！！
Ahoy!
きゅっ きゅっ きゅるん きゅっ きゅっ きゅるんるん
Kyu kyu kyurun, kyu kyu kyurun.
恋する 気持ち 17才
A heart in love, sweet 17.
0時になっちゃうワ オトナの時間
It's midnight, adult time!
やっぱり キラキラ もっと クラクラ
Brilliant and sparkling, making me dizzy!
ド・キ・ド・キ し て rouge ?
Does your pulse race through the rouge?
まだ早い ♡
Not yet, it's too early!
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
Not guilty! Not guilty! Beautiful girl not guilty!
マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！
Marine! Marine! Marine is not guilty!
やっぱり キラキラ もっと クラクラ
Brilliant and sparkling, making me dizzy!
“マリン”じゃなくて
It's not just \"Marine\",
“マリン船長”だろうん！？
It's \"Captain Marine\", you know?!
ド・キ・ド・キ し て rouge ?
Do your pulse passed through the rouge?
いきますよー！
Here we go!
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
Not guilty! Not guilty! Beautiful girl not guilty!
マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！
Marine! Marine! Marine is not guilty!
やっぱり キラキラ もっと クラクラ
Brilliant and sparkling, making me dizzy!
ねえ、言ったよね？
Hey, didn't you say it?
年齢なんて関係ないってさ
Age doesn't matter at all!
そうゆうめんどさいのも含めて愛してくれるって
You'll love me even with all my flaws.
ねえねえ、言ったよね？言ってない？
Hey hey, didn't you say it? Did you not?
ふーん、そういうこというんだ
Hmm, so that's how it is.
ちなみにこの船では
By the way, on this ship,
美少女無罪が適用されますけど？
\"Not guilty for beautiful girls\" applies!
まかせて！魔法で若返り
Leave it to me! Magic makes me young again.
ヒミツの素顔はキミにだけトクベツですー？
My secret true face is just for you!
Ah… アタシ厄介よ
Ah... I'm a handful.
Ah… 港なんかじゃしがないわ 近頃はね
Ah... I can't get excited at ports anymore.
宝島にしてほしい気分
I feel like turning it into a treasure island!
出航──！！
Set sail!
キュートは正義 美少女無罪
Cute is justice, beautiful girls are not guilty.
キミの一番目指して ヨーソロー！
Aimed to be your number one, steady as she goes!
本当は自信ないけど 頑張っちゃう
I'm actually not confident, but I'll do my best!
ahoy！！
Ahoy!
きゅっ きゅっ きゅるん きゅっ きゅっ きゅるん
Kyu kyu kyurun, kyu kyu kyurun.
恋する 気持ち 17才
A heart in love, sweet 17.
0時になっちゃうワ オトナの時間
It's midnight, adult time!
やっぱり キラキラ もっと クラクラ
Brilliant and sparkling, making me dizzy!
ド・キ・ド・キ し て rouge ?
Does your pulse race through the rouge?
まだ早い ♡
Not yet, it's too early!
だっだっ ダメですか？
I-I-Is it no good?
フリルの召し物着たらば
If I wear frilly clothes...
（そんなこと、ないよ）
(No, that's not true!)
だっだっ だって 魔女っ子になってみたい
B-B-Because I want to try being a magical girl!
ギリギリ有罪！？
Barely guilty?!
進路はなんない星
Our course is to Whatever-Star.
ちょっぴり足んない積極性？
Lacking a bit of assertiveness?
結局キミももっと若い子？
In the end, do you prefer younger girls too?
なんにしたって見捨てないでキミたち！
No matter what, don't abandon us, you guys!
（ちょっとイイコト見せてみたーい！）
(Want to see something nice?!)
Ah… たまにいじけちゃう
Ah... Sometimes I sulk.
Ah… それでもいいの？
Ah... Is that okay?
年頃だもん 本気になっちゃう
I'm at that age, so I get serious.
嵐の中も
Even through stormy seas,
一緒に、行こう？
shall we go together?
出航──！！
Set sail!
ハートにチャーム 美少女無罪
Charm on your heart, beautiful girls are not guilty.
あれあれどうした？
Well, well, what's wrong?
めんどさいよなんて言っちゃってさ
You complain that it's troublesome, but still...
かまってくれるキミが好き
I love you for paying attention to me!
ahoy！！
Ahoy!
きゅっ きゅっ きゅるん きゅっ きゅっ きゅるんるん
Kyu kyu kyurun, kyu kyu kyururun.
優しくしてね 17才
Be gentle with me, sweet 17.
突っ込んで経験値 お楽しみchu ♡
Dive into experience, enjoy chu ♡
やっぱり キラキラ もっと クラクラ
Brilliant and sparkling, making me dizzy!
ド・キ・ド・キ し て rouge ?
Does your pulse race through the rouge?
あぁ、お許しくだーたい！
Ah, please forgive me!
このマリンの……
This Marine's...
魅力！魔力！抗不可力！
Charm! Magic! Irresistible force!
──“罪な女”ね？
You're a \"sinful woman\", huh?
離さないで つかまっていて
Don't let go, hold on tight!
世界の広さ 見せたげるから！
I'll show you how big the world is!
ド・キ・ド・キして rouge ?
Has your pulse passed through the rouge?
いきますよー！
Here we go!
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
No fault, no fault! Not guilty!
マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！
Marine, Marine, Marine is not guilty!
胸を張れ 今を生きるその意味を
Hold your head high and embrace the meaning of now,
眩しい日も 巡る日も 確かめて進め
through both bright and changing days, forge ahead!
変わらないさ 海賊だ
Unchanging, we are pirates!
キュートは
Cuteness is
正義！
justice!
ほら、キミたちが
Hey, you guys...
どうですかー？
How is everyone doing?
イエーイ！
Yeah!
あ、そうだ挨拶しないと。
Oh right, we need to do our greetings.
挨拶挨拶！
Greetings, greetings!
えーっと、あ、じゃあちょっと考えてきたから。
Well, I've thought of something.
あのね、えっとマリンが「アホーイ」って言ったら、「アホーイ、はい」
If Marine says "Ahoy", you say "Ahoy, yes!"
あ、はーいって、言ってくださいね。
Make sure to say "yes".
あんな感じで、体のようにはいてまずマリン色に染めよう。
Like that, let's dye everyone in Marine colors!
あ、そうですね。一応初手ですから。
Ah, right. Since it's the opening.
せっかくなんでペンライト赤色でお願いします！
Please use red penlights!
お願いしまーす！
Please!
レッド、レッド、あ、きれい。どうも！
Red, red, oh, lovely. Thanks!
ありがとうございます！どうもありがとうございます、できましたよ。
Thank you very much! We did it!
じゃあ、いきますよ！
Well then, here we go!
えーっと、どうだったかな？あ、はーい！
Um, how was it again? Ah, ahoy!
ホロライブ…あ、ちょっと待って、アホーイって言った今、みんな。
Hololive... wait, everyone just said "Ahoy".
みんなアホーイって今言った？
Did everyone just say "Ahoy"?
ちょっと待って、マリン、好き勝手言いすぎない？
Wait a minute, aren't you doing whatever you want?
ちょっと言って、お・っ・ぱ・つ・で！
Tell them, with "oppatsu-de!"
はい、アホーイって言ったらアホーイって言ってくださいね。
Yes, when I say "Ahoy", please say "Ahoy".
いきますよー！
Here we go!
アホーイ！
Ahoy!
おおーー！
Ooh!
あ、素敵素敵素敵！えー何ですか？ホロライブ3期生、えーなんです？宝石を改造するセクシーの、宝石のマリンです！
Hololive 3rd Gen, sexy jeweler Marine!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
さすがあなただね。じゃあ行きますよ、みんな！
As expected of you. Now let's go, everyone!
えー、ライトブルーにしてください！お願いします、あなたの色に…あ！ブルーじゃないよ！
Please make it light blue! Wait, not blue!
あ、ブルー！ライトブルー、ライトブルーです！今のはライトブルーなんです！
Ah, blue! Light blue, it's light blue!
じゃあ、いきますよ、みんな！
Well then, here we go everyone!
かなただーー！
It's Kanata!
初期のピアは握力50キロ！うーうー握りつぶすぞ！ホロライブ来てから友達増えたぞ！
My grip strength is 50kg! I'll crush you!
イヤー！
Yeah!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
と いう こと で ね、この、このボクたちの「ふ」という漢字はですね、あの、韓国、インドネシアでライブビューイング、あ、お顔を出しているということで、そうなんです！
So, our kanji "Fu" is for live viewings in Korea and Indonesia!
聞いてるかみんな！韓国の皆さん、インドネシアの皆さん！
Can you hear us? Everyone in Korea and Indonesia!
はーい！見てるということでね、ぜひライブの感想…
Yes! Watching us, so please share your thoughts...
ハッシュタグ「ホロライブフェス EXPO アンダーバーデイワン」でSNSにアップしてください！お願いします！
Please upload to SNS with the hashtag "#HololiveFesExpo_Day1"!
はーい！と、でもさ、せっかく皆さんいらっしゃいますから、
Yes! But since everyone is here,
なんかやる？やっちゃう？ちょっと波作っちゃう？
should we do something? Make some waves?
え、いきなり作っ…ちょっと待って。いったんさ、あれやる？男の子女の子みたいな。
Eh, suddenly? Wait, should we do the boy and girl thing?
え、じゃあ、うん。
Eh, well, yeah.
じゃあ、みんな行くよ！男の子ーー！
Well then, everyone goes! Boys!
よー！うおー！
Yay! Whoa!
女の子少ないかもしれないから、頑張ってでかい声出してね。
There might be few girls, so shout loudly!
でかい声出してね！いくよ！女の子ーー！
Speak up! Here we go! Girls!
うおおおー！きれいな声が！女の子いる！見えてるよ！
Whoa! Such lovely voices! There are girls! I see you!
ありがとう！嬉しいです！
Thank you! I'm so happy!
両方行こう、両方！
Let's do both!
あ、じゃあね、せーの！どっちもー！どっちもー！
Alright, ready, set! Both! Both!
イヤー！
Yeah!
楽しい！
It's so much fun!
楽しいですねよ
It's really fun, right?
あ、波打つる？
Ah, it's rippling?
波打つる！波打つる！
It's rippling! It's rippling!
え、ゆっくり！ゆっくり！こっちから行こ！こっちから！
Um, slowly! Slowly! Let's go from this side! From this side!
みんな怪我しないようにね？マジ、ウェーブ作んな、いける？
Everyone be careful not to get hurt, okay? Seriously, don't make a wave—can you do it?
ウェーブ作れる？
Can you make a wave?
おー！
Whoa!
じゃ、行くよ！
Alright, here we go!
ゆっくりね、ゆっくりね。
Slowly, okay, slowly.
せーの、ほー！
Ready, set, whoa!
あー綺麗！綺麗！
Ah, it's so pretty! Pretty!
綺麗！綺麗！綺麗！綺麗よ、いいよ！
Pretty! Pretty! Pretty! It's so pretty, good job!
よし！次行くよ！
Alright! Next is going back!
次逆行くよ！逆！せーの、ほーー！
Next, let's go the other way! The other way! Ready, set, whoa—!
わーー！はははは！
Whoa—! Hahaha!
みんなーー！
Everyone—!
あ、綺麗！すごい！ありがとうございます！
Ah, pretty! Amazing! Thank you very much!
だ、すごい綺麗！
It's so, so pretty!
うまっ！
So good!
上手！みんな上手上手！
Great job! Everyone's doing great!
あったかーい！
So warm!
やばい、感動。
Man, I'm so touched.
褒めて、ありがとう！
Praise us, thank you!
さあ、はい！
Now, yes!
かなちゃーん！
Kanata-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
そして皆さん！
And everyone!
はーい！
Yes!
ここで重大なお知らせがあります。なになに？
We have an important announcement here. What is it?
なんと無料パートは...ここまです！
It turns out the free part... ends right here!
無料パート！
The free part!
えーー！？
What?!
うそーー！
No way!
えーー！？
What?!
概要欄からチケットの購入お願いします！お願いします！
Please purchase tickets from the description box! Please!
よろしくお願いします！お願いします！お願いします！
Thank you very much! Please! Please!
やっちゃう？
Shall we do it?
やってちゃおっか！
Let's do it!
ま、最初ハートで出てきたしさ、私たち。
Well, we came out making heart shapes at first, right, the two of us.
さいご、まだまだここからね、あるのでね、ちょっと最後ね、最初の登場のポーズでもう一回...
And finally, there's still more to come from here, so for the very end, let's do our opening pose once more...
あ、そうですね、終わりかえ...
Ah, that's right, since it's the end...
はい、まだまだ続くから...
Yes, it still continues, so...
頑張って楽しんでくださいね！
Please do your best and enjoy!
楽しんで！
Enjoy!
はーい！はーい！
Yes! Yes!
じゃあ、いくよ！
Well then, here we go!
うん！
Yeah!
せーの！キャプチャー・ザ・モーメント！
Ready, set! Capture the Moment!
無料パートは終了いたしました！ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free part has ended! Thank you for watching!
The free part has ended. Thank you for watching!